<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A hue and crie after the Earl of Clarendon.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1667</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B03708</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing H3289</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide C.20.f.2[71]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide C.20.f.4[100]</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99884971</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99884971</idno>
            <idno type="VID">182770</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B03708)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 182770)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; A1:1[72]; A4:2[101])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A hue and crie after the Earl of Clarendon.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[S.l. :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Printed in the year of Clarendon's confusion, 1667.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Verse: "FRom Dunkirk-House there lately ran away ..."</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Clarendon, Edward Hyde, --  Earl of, 1609-1674 --  Poetry --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="poem">
            <pb facs="tcp:182770:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 2 -->
            <head>A HUE AND CRIE AFTER The Earl of CLARENDON.</head>
            <lg>
               <l>FRom <hi>Dunkirk-Houſe</hi> there lately ran away</l>
               <l>A Traytor, whom you are defir'd to ſtay.</l>
               <l>You by theſe marks and ſigns may th'Traytor know,</l>
               <l>He's troubled with the Gout in feet below:</l>
               <l>Pity it is, it vex'd no other part;</l>
               <l>'Tis pity but long ſince 't had pain'd his Heart:</l>
               <l>Had it, I'm ſure 't had ſav'd ſome thouſand Lives,</l>
               <l>And thouſands that are Widows, had been Wives:</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Thouſands</hi> that <hi>Orphans</hi> are, ſo had not <hi>been,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But their dear Parents ſtill alive had ſeen:</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Dunkirk</hi> by <hi>England</hi> ſtill had been poſſeſt,</l>
               <l>Inſtead of being turn'd into <hi>a Neſt</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Of <hi>Gallick Pirates:</hi> Thoſe Ships that by <hi>Flames</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Did lately <hi>periſh,</hi> ſtill had kept their <hi>Names.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Scotch-<hi>Cittadels</hi> had ſtood; and th' ſtones that came</l>
               <l>From <hi>Pauls,</hi> might have conduc'd t' have ſtopt that <hi>Flame</hi>
               </l>
               <l>That not long ſince <hi>that ancient Pile did burn,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And turn'd it into its own <hi>Fun'ral Vrn.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Ships that were <hi>captive led by hoſtile hand,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Had ſtill <hi>remain'd the Bulwarks of our Land;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And <hi>we</hi> whom <hi>Conquered Foes</hi> did late invade,</l>
               <l>Might unto us ſtill them have ſubject made:</l>
               <l>And might have kept, without much coſt or pain,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Plantations,</hi> that will coſt <hi>dear</hi> to regain:</l>
               <l>This <hi>hopeful Blade</hi> being conſcious of his <hi>Crimes,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And <hi>ſmelling</hi> how the <hi>current</hi> of the <hi>times</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Ran croſs, forſakes his <hi>Palace</hi> and <hi>the Town,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Like</hi> ſome preſaging Rat th'houſe ere't falls down;</l>
               <l>Or like <hi>Sea-Monſter,</hi> when the Waves 'gin t'roar,</l>
               <l>Retires, and waits until the Storm be o'er:</l>
               <l>So he, preſaging Storm, away is fled;</l>
               <l>Knowing 't would coſt him loſs of <hi>Hide</hi> and Head,</l>
               <l>Shou'd he remain. 'Tis pity that the Womb</l>
               <l>That bare him, did not alſo prove his <hi>Tomb.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>'Tis pity that this <hi>Cock'trice</hi> had not been</l>
               <l>Cruſht in the Egg, ere he the Light had ſeen:</l>
               <l>Or that long ſince he had of Vital Breath</l>
               <l>Bereaved been by ſome untimely Death;</l>
               <l>It had been well for us: No Days that are</l>
               <l>Mark'd with <hi>Red Letters</hi> in our <hi>Calendar,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Had more deſerv'd <hi>Remembrance;</hi> hardly thoſe</l>
               <l>That <hi>Popiſh Plots</hi> againſt us did diſcloſe.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>But ſince he's fled, who ere can find him out,</l>
               <l>And bring him back; an <hi>Action</hi> without doubt,</l>
               <l>Grateful to <hi>England</hi> will perform; and he</l>
               <l>Shall with three Nations thanks rewarded be:</l>
               <l>If poſsible alive let him be brought,</l>
               <l>That for thoſe <hi>helliſh miſchiefs</hi> he hath wrought,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>He</hi> may be <hi>publiſhed</hi> in publick view,</l>
               <l>And <hi>Hangman</hi> with the <hi>Devil</hi> receive his due.</l>
               <l>If not, 'twould be a <hi>meritorious Deed,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For any man to make <hi>his Heart to Bleed,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>With Stab of Dagger; any way; ſoth' World</l>
               <l>Be rid of him; ſo he to <hi>Hell</hi> be hurld:</l>
               <l>Whither almoſt we may conclude he'll goe,</l>
               <l>and ſtir up Feuds amongſt the Fiends below,</l>
               <l>Till a new <hi>hell</hi> for him they find: No times</l>
               <l>Can inſtance in the like flagitious Crimes,</l>
               <l>By any Perſon done: A thouſand Lives,</l>
               <l>And ruine of ten thouſand that ſurvives,</l>
               <l>Lie on his Charge. Therefore when ever he</l>
               <l>Shall periſh, let a general Jubilee</l>
               <l>Be kept throughout the Land, that all may know</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Treaſon ſtill works the Traytors Overthrow.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed in the Year of <hi>CLARENDON'S</hi> Confuſion, 1667.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
